Guide to the New-York Historical Society Librarian Dorothy C. Barck Records 1921-1954 NYHS-RG 19
New-York Historical Society
- American Association for State and Local History, 1943 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 10)
  Includes correspondence about a joint meeting between the American Historical Association and the AASLH in December 1943 at the N-YHS; materials related to Barck's participation in the Committee to Publicize American History; and four handbook entries and completed handbook survey forms (by the Historical Society of Montana, the Daughters of Utah Pioneers, the Utah State Historical Society, and the Historical Society of the State of Idaho) for the Handbook of Historical Societies.
- Annual Reports, Library, 1941-47 (2 folders), 1941-1947 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 11-12)
  The 1944 Annual Report includes a summary list, with descriptions, of that year's accessions, and detailed statistics about reading room usage and reference inquiries. 1945 and 1947 also include detailed acquisition lists.
- Annual Reports, Library, 1951 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 13)
  Primarily notes related to the composition of the 1951 Library Annual Report.
- Annual Reports to New York State, 1944-48, 1944-1948 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 14)
  Includes copies of completed Library Reports for the State Education Department in New York for the years 1944-1948.
- Archival Displays at New-York Historical Society, 1951 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 15)
  Includes a copy of Barck's speech "How Archival Displays are Arranged by the New-York Historical Society" delivered at the annual meeting of the Society of American Archivists in October of 1951.
- Blizzard Men of 1888, 1937-1945 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 16)
  A large amount of correspondence from 1937-1945 related to the Blizzard Men of 1888, such as reminiscences, activities, a list of Blizzard Men letters as of 1937, and requests for the 1937 and 1935 Bulletin articles.
- Forms, etc., circa 1940 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 17)
  Includes membership application forms, photostat/photograph order forms, a pass for taking objects out of the building, a researcher request form, an application for the use of manuscripts, and an employment application.
- Gates, Horatio, 1946-1953 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 18)
  Primarily includes research notes compiled by Barck while researching Horatio Gates genealogy for Pierre S. duPont and Margaret Kane.
- Gorgets, 1924-1933 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 1)
  Includes notes, letters, and pictures about gorgets, and a copy of Alexander Wall's 1933 Quarterly article entitled "Early Flags Used by the United States."
- Grenzebach, 1937-1938 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 2)
  This folder contains materials relating to the publication of an article about the house of John Nicholas Grenzebach written by Barck. The article was published in the July issue of the Quarterly Bulletin. Also included are letters Barck sent to the descendants of Grenzebach during her research and a draft of the article.
- Krout Club (published New-York Historical Society Quarterly, July 1938) (Offsite-box 24, Folder 3)
  Includes notes for and a draft copy of Barck's article "The Krout Club."
- Lantern Slides/Photographs/Photostats, 1922-1945 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 4)
  Notes about slides owned, loaned, and wanted by N-YHS.
- List of New York Inhabitants, 1775 (published New-York Historical Society Quarterly, January 1939) (Offsite-box 24, Folder 5)
  Includes Barck's notes and a draft copy of the article for the Quarterly titled "New York City Inhabitants Who Returned City-Owned Muskets in 1775."
- Manuscripts, 1942 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 6)
  Includes notes and lists of manuscript collections at the N-YHS.
- Map and Print Room, 1942-1943 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 7)
  Attendance and usage charts, and a list of telephone questions for the Map and Print Room
- Memos, etc. (2 folders), 1931-1953 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 8-9)
  Includes staff memos and notes, research notes for reference questions, library staff announcements for meetings and protocol, requisition applications, arrangements for the Strawberry Festival Garden Party, and an announcement about the private opening of the Pirie MacDonald exhibition.
- National Archives Emergency Evacuation Procedures, 1941 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 10)
  A copy of the National Archives publication The Care of Records in a National Emergency, with some underlining and checkmarks. This booklet provides advice for the care of records during an emergency, such as in wartime.
- Newspapers, 1941-1952 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 11)
  Includes lists of newspapers owned by the N-YHS, and a list of newspapers being sold by the New York Public Library.
- N-YHS Exhibitions, 1943-1947 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 12)
  Includes a copy of a booklet titled "Selected Americana Exclusive of New York from the Library of the New-York Historical Society"; a diagram of the east corridor with measurements of display cases and walls; exhibition schedules for 1946-47 and 1943-44; text of labels for the George Clinton Special Exhibition; information about the First Inauguration of Washington as President exhibition; and the exhibition about John Peter Zenger and the liberty of the American Press.
- N-YHS Collections (Misc.), circa 1940s (Offsite-box 24, Folder 13)
  Lists of various collections at the N-YHS, and recommendations for acquisition.
- N-YHS Library, 1942-1950 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 14)
  Includes several lists of interesting donations to the library compiled for publication in the Quarterly, a description of the library, its staff, and collections.
- N-YHS Publications, 1921-1945 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 15)
  Includes announcements and order forms for various books published by N-YHS, lists of publications in the John Divine Jones Fund Series of Histories and Memoirs, a list of articles by William L. Calver available in the Quarterly Bulletin, and numbers of copies of books held by the N-YHS, some of which were for sale.
- Notes on N-YHS Annex #1 (Straus, 5 W. 76th St.) and Annex #2 (Fleischmann, 4 W. 77th St.), circa 1930s (Offsite-box 24, Folder 16)
  Notes include chains of title, building costs, and descriptions of floor plans.
- Notes re: Removal and Retrieval of Stored Items, 1942-43, 1942-1943 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 17)
  Notes about the packing of materials to be stored during the war. Includes inventories of cartons, photograph orders for n-YHS's records of stored materials, and a retrieval plan for the first trip back from storage.
- Personal and/or Quasi-Official Correspondence, 1948-51 (3 folders), 1942-1953 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 18-20)
  Includes personal letters, holiday cards, professional membership materials (including American Association for State and Local History), and a copy of a speech "Journals Not Indexed in Periodical Indexes" which Barck presented to the Librarians Section of the A. A. M.
- Pintard Descendants (2 folders), 1937-1953 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 1-2)
  All correspondence with Pintard descendants. Includes some correspondence relating to N-YHS's 1941 exhibit about John Pintard, the publication of Pintard letters, and the many gifts N-YHS received from Pintard descendants.
- Pintard Diaries, 1932-1937 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 3)
  Correspondence concerning the acquiring of Pintard manuscript materials, primarily to or from Alexander Wall.
- Report re: Cataloging NYC Prints and Photos, 1941 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 4)
  A report from a N-YHS employee, Henry B. Hoffmann, about his cataloging work with New York City views from 1936-1940.
- Wall, A. J., and other N-YHS Employees, 1943-1946 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 5)
  Includes a brief professional and personal biography of Alexander Wall, an obituary for Edmund Bramhall Child, an informal biography of Edmund B. Child, and a list of men in the service.
- For Sale Letters (9 of 15 folders), 1926, 1930s-1951 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 6-14)
  Frequent correspondents: M. C. Simons, Williams Book Store, Symmachus Trading Co., Goodspeeds Book Shop, Arthur H. Clark Company, P. and H. Bliss, Paul H. Ritchey, Schulte's Book Store, C. E. H. Whitlock, A. Buschke, William F. Kelleher, Charles E. Tuttle Company, Ira J. Friedman, Argosy Book Stores, Howard S. Mott., and Robert W. Lull. Includes envelope samples from Bishop Paper Company.
- For Sale Letters (6 of 15 folders), 1945-1954 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 1-6)
  Frequent correspondents: P. Richard Whittemore of House of Whittemore, C. E. H. Whitlock, Howard S. Mott, and American Library Service.
- Inquiries by Mail Notebook, 1947-1949 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 7)
  Contains Barck's notebook logging mail assigned to various Library staff for resolution during 1947-1949. Included are the names of the inquirers, the date of the letter, the subject, and the name of the responsible N-YHS staff member.
- Inquiries by Mail Notebook, 1950-1952 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 8)
  Contains Barck's notebook logging mail assigned to various Library staff for resolution during 1950-1952. Included are the names of the inquirers, the date of the letter, the subject, and the name of the responsible N-YHS staff member.
- Letters Answered Directly by Barck, 1945-1950 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 9)
  A notebook log recording each letter answered by Barck, with names, addresses, and a tiny bit of subject matter.
- Telephone Index, undated (Offsite-box 26, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Reference Notes, 1930s (Offsite-box 26, Folder 11)
- Pirie MacDonald Exhibition. Index Cards of Invitation Mailings, [1943] (Offsite-box 27, Cards -)